# Jake deVarennes

# Software Engineer

✓ devarennesjacob@gmail.com

♦ Houston, TX k jakedevarennes.com jakedevar in jakedevar

# **₽** PROFILE

Software Engineer with two years of experience in both Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems. Led architecture design with a team of four to build Constellation, a geo-distributed load-testing framework. Which can handle up to 10,000 virtual users from all 26 AWS regions at once.

# EXPERIENCE

# **Software Engineer, Co-creator,** Constellation □

2022 - present

Constellation is an open-source tool that provides a simple command line interface for deploying geo-distributed load testing on all 26 AWS hosted regions.

- Researched existing products to find most impactful features and explore architectural challenges
- Spearheaded development of the data-aggregation software using Node.js and AWS SDK engineered for a capacity of over 130 requests per second
- Constructed the data visualizer which provides a comprehensive way to ingest data returned from the load generation test from all 26 AWS regions
- Developed CLI command allowing users to accomplish with a single command on Constellation, which would take over 7 API calls to AWS to accomplish
- Managed engineering team that created a buffer system which decreased the data loss to 0% at a rate of over 130 Rps
- Wrote code from scratch which replaces the functionality of 3 open-source tools that reduced overall API complexity
- · Engineered data ingestion and retrieval system optimized for high read volume and complex analytical queries over large datasets
- Collaborated with a remote team of engineers from the US, New Zealand & Canada, across four time zones involving daily stand-ups and pair programming
- Authored Constellation's comprehensive case study defining the problem domain, architectural design decision, and technical challenges faced when developing Constellation

#### **Software Engineer,** *Self-employed* □

2021 - 2022

Developed open-source web applications with technologies such as Node, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.

- Bin of Requests: A Node.js application built using Express, MongoDB, Postman, and PostgreSQL to capture and monitor HTTP requests
- JobQuery: A Node.js job keyword tracking software built with Express, MongoDB, Puppeteer, and React/Redux that processes 900 job listings at once and analyzes the top keywords present in each listing
- Swillreno.com: Architected website using Wordpress and saved company over \$750.00 and two weeks of development time

## Sales Associate, Multiple

2016 - 2021

- · Became number one in contract volume at a medical waste removal startup using email marketing, cold calls, and in-person meetings with medical professionals
- Became one of the top 5% of salespeople in the region
- Initiated and managed business relationships with key customers

# SKILLS

Languages (JavaScript/Node.js, Typescript, Ruby, Go, PostgreSQL, CSS, HTML)

Cloud (AWS, DynamoDB, Lambda, EC2, API Gateway, S3, Timestream, Digital Ocean, Fargate, DynamoDB)

Libraries & Frameworks (React, Redux, jQuery, Express, Jest, Handlebars, Puppeteer, MaterialUI, Bootstrap)

Other (Docker, Git, GitHub, Neovim, Linux, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, MongoDB, Nginx)

### **EDUCATION**

University of Nevada Reno, BA General Studies

Software Engineering, Launch School